Horace Freeland Judson Collection 1968-1978 Mss.B.J92
American Philosophical Society
- Transcripts of oral history interviews, 1968-1978; 2 boxes
  - Pauling, Linus, 1971-1975; 20 pages (Box 2)
    Dec. 23, 1975, Peter Pauling's apartment, London
    Behavioral genetics, IQ; Biochemistry and organic chemistry; Biographical and personal data; Ethical issues; Eugenics; History of biology, especially genetics; Molecular genetics; Philosophy of science; Publication -- The Eighth Day of Creation; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Pauling, Peter, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Feb. 1, 1970, laboratory at University College, London
  - Perrin, David, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Nov. 15, 1976, Institut Pasteur, Paris
  - Perutz, Max (2 folders), 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    May 8, 1968, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    May 29-30, 1968, Royal Society, London
    Sept. 24, 1969, letter to Judson
    Apr. 3, 1970, train from London to Cambridge
    Aug. 1970, his house, Sedley Taylor Road, Cambridge
    Dec. 4-6, 1970, his house, Sedley Taylor Road, Cambridge
    Jan. 5, 1971, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    Jan. 23, 1971, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    Oct. 2, 1971, Paris
    Apr. 1972, seminar series, Cornell University
    Dec. 18, 1974, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    Feb. 15, 1975, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    May 23, 1975, Peterhouse and old Cavendish Laboratory, Cambridge
    Jan. 19, 1976, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    Jan. 23, 1976, lunch with Klug, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    Jan. 31, 1976, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    Nov. 11, 1977, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    Nov. 19, 1977, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    Feb. 3, 1978, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
  - Phillips, David, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Jan. 8, 1971, his laboratory at University of Oxford
  - Pollack, Robert, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Jun. 3, 1973, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory
    [Jun. 4, 1973], Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory
    Jun. 27, 1973, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory
    Jul. 30, 1975, editorial office of The New Yorker
  - Potter, Lincoln, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    1 Feb. [1971], University College, London
  - Ptashne, Mark, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    10 Aug. 1977, Biological Laboratories, Harvard University
  - Rich, Alexander, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    12 Feb. 1971, his office at Massachusetts Institute of Technology
    17 Mar. 1971, his office at Massachusetts Institute of Technology
    9 Aug. 1977, his office at Massachusetts Institute of Technology
  - Ruderman, Warren, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    27 Apr. 1978, by telephone to Interactive Radiation, New Jersey
  - Sanger, Frederick, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    6 Jan. 1971, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    22 Jan. [1971], MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    2 Feb. 1976, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
  - Sayre, Anne, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Jun. 1972, her house, St. James, Long Island
  - Schachman, Howard, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    4 Apr. 1978, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
  - Schmidt, Benno, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    3 Oct. 1975, his office, New York City
  - Shils, E.A., 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    23 Aug. 1976, letter from Judson
  - Singer, Maxine, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    25 Jul. 1977, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland
  - Smith, John, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    -See also Brenner, Sydney, 28 Feb. 1976
    Jan. 1977, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
  - Spear, Walter Eric, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    6 Feb. 1976, letter from Judson
    16 Feb. 1976, letter to Judson
  - Stent, Gunther, 1976-1977; 31 pages (Box 2)
    17 Sept. 1976, letter to Judson
    15 Sept. 1977, letter to Judson
    24 Sept. 1977, at his brother's apartment, Maida Vale, London
    25 Sept. 1977, letter to Judson
    2 Nov. 1977, letter to Judson
    Beadle, George Wells; California Institute of Technology; Crick, Francis H. C.; Cytogenetics; Delbruck, Max; Embryology, developmental genetics; History of biology, especially genetics; Honors -- Nobel Prize; Molecular genetics; Monod, Jacques; Pauling, Linus; Publication -- The Eighth Day of Creation; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Watson, James D.
  - Stoker, Michael, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    [28 Jan. 1971], Imperial Cancer Research Fund Laboratory, Lincoln's Inn Fields, London
  - Stokes, Alexander, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    11 Aug. 1976, his house, Welwyn Garden City
    6 Oct. 1976, letter to Judson
  - Swift, Hewson, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    [Oct. 1973], his house, Hyde Park, Chicago
  - Szent-Gyorgi, Andrew Gabriel, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    12 May 1978, by telephone to Brandeis University
  - Temins, Howard, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    27 Oct. 1978, University of Wisconsin
  - Terheggen, Heinz Georg, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    30 Oct. 1969, letter from Stanfield Rogers to Terheggen
    1 Dec. 1969, letter from Terheggen to Stanfield Rogers
    8 Sept. 1970, letter from Judson to Time Science
    23 Oct. 1971, by telephone from Paris
    2 Feb. 1972, by telephone to Cologne
  - Thomas, Charles, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    6 Oct. 1973, Harvard Medical School
  - Tissières, Alfred, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    16 Feb. 1977, Royal Society, London
  - Travers, Andrew, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Ullman, Agnès, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Watson, James D., 1970-1978; 56 pages (Box 2)
    1 Dec. 1970, Imperial Cancer Research Fund, Lincoln's Inn Field, London
    16 Mar. 1971, Biological Laboratories, Harvard University
    24-25 Sept. 1973, Biological Laboratories, Harvard University
    30 Sept. 1973, on plane to Washington
    Sept. 1973, lecture, Science Center, Harvard University
    5 Oct. 1973, Biological Laboratories, Harvard University
    11 Apr. 1975, letter to Judson
    8 Sept. 1975, letter to Judson
    5 Nov. 1975, letter from Judson
    20 Nov. 1975, letter to Judson
    26 Aug.-24 Sept. 1976, letters from Judson re Watson
    6 Jul. 1978, letter to Judson
    20 Oct. 1978, letter to Judson
    Bacteriophage and viral genetics; Biochemistry and organic chemistry; Biographical and personal data; Cancer, chemotherapy; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Crick, Francis H. C.; Cytogenetics; Delbruck, Max; Educational matters; History of biology, especially genetics; Lectures, public speaking; Molecular genetics; Pauling, Linus; Philosophy of science; Political issues; Publication -- The Double Helix; Publication -- The Eighth Day of Creation; University of Chicago; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Weil, Adrienne, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    -See Perutz, Max, Oct. 2, 1971
  - Wilkins, Maurice [closed to researchers], 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Jun. 26, 1971, Versailles and Paris
    Sept. 15, 1975, King's College, London
    Nov. 18, 1975-Jan. 15, 1976, letters between Judson and Wilkins
    Mar. 12, 1976, King's College, London
    Apr. 28, 1976-Oct. 1, 1978, letters between Judson and Wilkins
    Nov. 24, 1978, by telephone from The New Yorker office to King's College, London
  - Wollman, Élie, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Jun. 17, 1977, by telephone to Institut Pasteur, Paris
    Jul. 5, 1978, by telephone to Institut Pasteur, Paris
  - Women at King's College [closed to researchers], 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    -See also Brown, Angela Martin
    -See also Fell, Dame Honor
    -See also Harrison, Pauline Cowan
    -See also Jackson, Sylvia Fitton
    -See also North, Margaret Pratt
    Sept. 3, 1976, letter to Marjorie M'Ewen from Judson
    Sept. 15, 1976, letter from M'Ewen to Judson
    Sept. 28. 1976, letter to Angela Martin Brown from Judson
    Jan. 21, 1977, letter to Margaret Pratt North from Judson
    Aug. 22, 1978, letter from Mary J. Fraser to Judson
    n.d., notes
  - Wyatt, Gerard, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Apr. 26, 1978, by telephone to his house, Kingston, Ontario
    [Apr. 29, 1978], by telephone to his house, Kingston, Ontario
  - Yanofsky, Charles, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Mar. 1, 1971, Palo Alto
  - Zamecnik, Paul, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Aug. 5, 1977, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston
    May 5, 1978, by telephone to Harvard Medical School
    Jun. 1, 1978, New York Academy of Sciences symposium, Barbizon Plaza Hotel
- Interviews with molecular biologists, 1968-1978; Mss.Rec.113a; 52.0 Tape(s)